[
  {
    "category": "Algebra",
    "answer": "4",
    "question": "2+2"},
  {
    "category": "Algebra",
    "answer": "16",
    "question": "4*4"},
  {
    "category": "Trigonometry",
    "answer": "0",
    "question": "sin(pi)"},
  {
    "category": "Trigonometry",
    "answer": "-1",
    "question": "cos(pi)"},
  {
    "category": "Trigonometry",
    "answer": "1",
    "question": "cos(2pi)"},
  {
    "category": "Calculus",
    "answer": "8x",
    "question": "4(x^2)"},
  {
    "category": "Calculus",
    "answer": "1/x",
    "question": "ln(x)"},
  {
    "category": "Calculus",
    "answer": "1",
    "question": "x"},
   {
    "category": "Calculus",
    "answer": "9",
    "question": "9x"},
  {
    "category": "Portmath",
    "answer": "105",
    "question": "http+smtp"},
  {
    "category": "Portmath",
    "answer": "1",
    "question": "telnet-ssh"},
   {
    "category": "Portmath",
    "answer": "421",
    "question": "https-ssh"},
    {
    "category": "Portmath",
    "answer": "465",
    "question": "https+ssh"},
  {
    "category": "Geography",
    "answer": "New York",
    "question": "America's smallest county in area"},
  {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Calvin Coolidge",
    "question": "Only president born on the 4th of July"},
  {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Social justice",
    "question": "Since Franklin D. Roosevelt and his New Deal coalition in the 1930s, the Democratic Party has also promoted a social liberal platform, supporting what?"},
  {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Abraham Lincoln",
    "question": "Who ran for president with the campaign slogan 'Vote yourself a Farm'?"},
  {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Grover Cleveland",
    "question": "Who was the first US president to be married in the White House?"},
     {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Martin Van Buren",
    "question": "Who was the first US president to be born an American Citizen? "},
     {
    "category": "Politics",
    "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
    "question": "Who was the first president to have a state car built to secret service standards"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "lion",
    "question": "House Lannister Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "direwolf",
    "question": "House Stark Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "rose",
    "question": "House Tyrell Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "trout",
    "question": "House Tully Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "stag",
    "question": "House Baratheon Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "flayed man",
    "question": "House Bolton Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "kraken",
    "question": "House Greyjoy Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "falcon",
    "question": "House Arryn Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "sun and spear",
    "question": "House Martell Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "GoT Sigils",
    "answer": "bear",
    "question": "House Mormont Sigil"},
  {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Lansing",
    "question": "Michigan" },
  {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Annapolis",
    "question": "Maryland" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "New York",
    "question": "New York" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Columbus",
    "question": "Ohio" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Boise",
    "question": "Idaho" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Springfield",
    "question": "Illinois" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Honolulu",
    "question": "Hawaii" },
    {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Dover",
    "question": "Delaware" },
   {
    "category": "State Capitals",
    "answer": "Frankfurt",
    "question": "Kentucky" },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Superman",
    "question": "Every Episode of Seinfeld mentions which superhero at least once?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "I want to Believe",
    "question": "What is the phrase of the UFO poster in Fox Mulders office in X-Files?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Kathleen Turner",
    "question": "Who played Chandler's father on Friends?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Survivor",
    "question": "What reality TV show debuted a Pontiac Aztec as their Season 1 Grand Prize?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Drew Barrymore",
    "question": "Youngest person to host Saturday Night Live?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Orange & Green",
    "question": "What colors is the Brady Bunch kitchen?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "Creed",
    "question": "What character becomes a wanted fugitive in the final season of The Office?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "TV",
    "answer": "The Flintstones",
    "question": "First Animated TV show made for prime-time television?",
    "citation": "https://www.usefultrivia.com/tv_trivia/"
  },
  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Bowhead whales",
    "question": "Which mammal has the longest lifespan? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Bats",
    "question": "What is the only mammal capable of true flight? ? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Bowhead whales",
    "question": "What is the largest of the great apes?? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Mountain Gorilla",
    "question": "Which mammal has the longest lifespan? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Giraffe ",
    "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Three-toed sloth ",
    "question": "What is the slowest animal? "},

  {
    "category": "Animals",
    "answer": "Bullfrog ",
    "question": "What animal never sleeps? "},
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "So far away",
    "question": "What lyric follows `Yesterday, all my troubles seemed`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "Twist and shout",
    "question": "What lyric follows `Well, shake it up, baby, now`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "Let it Be",
    "question": "What lyric follows `Mother Mary comes to me, speaking words of wisdom`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "Like a dog",
    "question": "What lyric follows `It's been a hard day's night, and I've been working`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "Gently weeps",
    "question": "What lyric follows `It's turning, while my guitar`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "And in my eyes",
    "question": "What lyric follows `Penny Lane is in my ears`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Beatles Lyrics",
    "answer": "With diamonds",
    "question": "What lyric follows `Lucy in the Sky`?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "The Forerunners",
    "question": "Who did the Covenant worship?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "Number 117",
    "question": "There were 150 spartan candidates. Which one reached the rank of Master Chief Petty Officer?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "The Precursors",
    "question": "Who did the Forerunners overthrow?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "Harvest",
    "question": "On what planet was the first contact between humans and the Covenant?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "Reach",
    "question": "What planet was the human's military headquarters?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "The Prophets",
    "question": "What alien race was the head of the governance of the Covenant?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Halo",
    "answer": "Eden",
    "question": "The Librarian made a garden to save humans from the Flood. What did she name it?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "Metal Oxide Semiconducting Field Effect Transistor",
    "question": "What does MOSFET stand for?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "Very High Speed Integrated Circuit Hardware Design Language",
    "question": "What does VHDL stand for?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "A Wheatstone Bridge",
    "question": "What four resistor circuit do loadcells use to measure force?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "The number of coils",
    "question": "What aspect of a transformer determines if the circuit will step up or step down voltage?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "8",
    "question": "How many wires are in a 100 mbps ethernet cable?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Circuits",
    "answer": "60",
    "question": "What frequency is the AC power in the U.S. powergrid?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "Woodrow Wilson",
    "question": "What US President went to JHU?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "He became the president of Princeton University",
    "question": "One US President went to JHU. What did he do after the presidency?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "The US Navy",
    "question": "MIT Lincoln Laboratory is the official FFRDC of the Air Force. JPL is the FFRDC of NASA. What government entity does the JHU APL support?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "2.5 billion dollars",
    "question": "Harvard is the second largest research university at an annual research budget of 1.7 billion dollars a year. How much research money does JHU spend annually, not including APL?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "Baltimore, Maryland",
    "question": "Where is JHU's Homewood Campus?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "Dr. Lanier Watkins",
    "question": "Who is the currect head of the JHU EP Computer Science Program?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "0",
    "question": "How many kids did Johns Hopkins have?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "Medicine",
    "question": "What was the first college of Johns Hopkins University?"
  },
  {
    "category": "JHU",
    "answer": "His cousin",
    "question": "Johns Hopkins fell in love and wanted to marry a girl in his teens. His family forbade it. Who was she?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "A feather of a pheonix",
    "question": "What is inside Harry's wand?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "Beedle the Bard",
    "question": "Who wrote the fairy tale 'The Tale of the Three Brothers?'"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "Nothing",
    "question": "What is inside the Elder Wand?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "He attacked three muggle boys after they assaulted his daughter",
    "question": "Why was Albus Dumbledore's father sentenced to Azkaban?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "Magical Beasts and Where to Find Them",
    "question": "What was the name of the textbook for Hagrid's class in Harry's first year at Hogwarts?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "1",
    "question": "How many true prophecies did Professor Trelawney have in her life?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "Neville Longbottom",
    "question": "Two children met all the criteria for the prophecy about Lord Voldemort: Harry Potter and ____________"
  },
  {
    "category": "Harry Potter",
    "answer": "His mouth",
    "question": "What did Harry use to catch his very first golden snitch?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "Captain",
    "question": "What the US Navy's rank that is equivalent to an Army Colonel?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "Battleship",
    "question": "What the most common type of ship in the US Navy?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "Zumwalt",
    "question": "What the class of the US Navy's new 'stealth ship'?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "O-7 or Rear Admiral",
    "question": "What is the minimum rank in the US Navy to be considered a flag officer?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "Russian pipeline",
    "question": "The largest non-nuclear explosion was caused by US malware. What did they blow up?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Military",
    "answer": "Air Force",
    "question": "What branch of the US military has produced the most astronauts?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Cars",
    "answer": "Subabro",
    "question": "What is a slang term for a bachelor that drives a Subaru?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Cars",
    "answer": "Coupe",
    "question": "What term is used to describe a model of car with only two doors?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Cars",
    "answer": "Lamborghini",
    "question": "Out of Ferrari, McLaren, and Lamborghini, which company does not have a Formula 1 team?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Cars",
    "answer": "Tesla",
    "question": "What US company makes the fastest production sedan?"
  },
  {
    "category": "Cars",
    "answer": "Germany",
    "question": "What country is BMW headquartered?"
  }
]
